<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dtaskai&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://dtaskai.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on dtaskai&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2022, Dominik Táskai</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 17:57:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dtaskai.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1001th K8s CPU limit article</title>
      <link>https://dtaskai.me/post/1001th-k8s-cpu-limit-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 17:57:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dtaskai.me/post/1001th-k8s-cpu-limit-article/</guid>
      <description>If you are somewhat into Kubernetes, then you have probably read the previous 1000 articles about why you should not be setting CPU limits, so why should you bother with going through this short post? Well, I will try my best to touch on the basics of how the CPU and memory works and how does that affect Kubernetes resource limits.
CPU requests To understand what CPU limits do, it is crucial to understand what setting CPU requests does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add fields with Kustomize patches without overwriting</title>
      <link>https://dtaskai.me/post/add-fields-with-kustomize-patches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 16:58:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dtaskai.me/post/add-fields-with-kustomize-patches/</guid>
      <description>The reason for this post is that we ran into this issue a few days ago and could not find sufficent information on how to set fields without overwriting them using Kustomize, so here it is:
To patch resources using Kustomize with either a strategic merge patch or a JSON6902 patch you have to add a target selector and a patch document to your Kustomization resource.
apiVersion: kustomize.config.k8s.io/v1beta1 kind: Kustomization metadata: name: patch namespace: namespace-to-patch spec: patches: - patch: | - op: add path: /spec/template/spec/securityContext value: runAsUser: 10000 fsGroup: 1337 - op: add path: /spec/template/spec/containers/0/securityContext value: readOnlyRootFilesystem: true allowPrivilegeEscalation: false runAsNonRoot: true capabilities: drop: - ALL target: kind: Deployment namespace: apps The problem with the above JSON6902 patches is that they are going to completely replace any other values inside your securityContext, instead of appending/adding the new values to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mTLS enforcement with OPA Gatekeeper</title>
      <link>https://dtaskai.me/post/mtls-enforcement-with-gatekeeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 10:25:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dtaskai.me/post/mtls-enforcement-with-gatekeeper/</guid>
      <description>Due to internal policies it might be mandatory to only allow mTLS-protected traffic inside your cluster between your services. To break this down into steps that can be easily implemented we need:
a way to enable mTLS in the cluster, for this we are going to use Linkerd an Ingress Controller, since Linkerd does not provide one by default, the choice here is going to be the NGINX Ingress Controller an approach that lets us ensure that every new service (be it a Deployment, Statefulset, DaemonSet or ReplicaSet), gets automatically meshed and thus enables mTLS traffic to and from the aforementioned service, the final piece to our puzzle is going to be one of OPA Gatekeeper&amp;rsquo;s new mutating CRDs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancel a launched goroutine</title>
      <link>https://dtaskai.me/post/go-cancel-a-launched-goroutine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 15:29:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dtaskai.me/post/go-cancel-a-launched-goroutine/</guid>
      <description>One of the more challenging tasks in the past few months was for me was to find a way to implement the following feature:
After a set amount of seconds (provided in the form of an environment variable) launch a goroutine which sends control data to another service with a way to cancel the whole process in case of an external event. If you come from perhaps a Java background then this task seems pretty trivial, you &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo; have to call the interrupt() function on your thread, but with goroutines this is not an option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timezone pitfall in Go and Docker</title>
      <link>https://dtaskai.me/post/go-timezone-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 15:08:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dtaskai.me/post/go-timezone-docker/</guid>
      <description>While working on a project I received a bug report that there is a 1 hour difference between dates at one part of my service and after an hour of trying to reproduce to issue, we came to the conclusion that the reason why it was so hard to track down was that our GKE cluster operates in the UTC timezone, while my local environment (and even our production cluster) is in the Europe/Budapest timezone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://dtaskai.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 19:58:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dtaskai.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi I&amp;rsquo;m a tech enthusiast currently working as a Junior DevOps Engineer in sunny (not really) Hungary. The goal of this site is to share my findings, tips and struggles that I run into during my journey on becoming a better engineer.
My tech stack is basically whatever I come across and interests me, but I write most things in Go.
I&amp;rsquo;m also a Certified Kubernetes Administrator and a Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
